Alexander Swensen

Nashville, Tennessee, United States

alex.swensen@gmail.com

(269) 861-4553

linkedin.com/in/alexswensen

Summary

Alexander Swensen is a software engineer with over 6 years of full-stack web development experience in various languages and frameworks.

Favorite languages include JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Node, and Go Favorite frameworks include React, Vue, Angular, Flask, & Django Has previous experience in AWS, as well as AAC Technologies such as Terraform and Ansible

Has driven change & growth both in technology & culture in previous roles.

Experience



tend Senior Software Engineer

Tend

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022 (4 months)

- Design, build, and deploy highly available multi-region AWS architecture.
- Design and deploy serverless self-healing data architecture in AWS, and Django.

Senior Software Engineer

Bulletin

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021 (7 months)

Led engineering, architecture, design, and product efforts to improve site reliability, SEO, and UX in a fast-paced environment. Also continued to develop high priority features valued by users. Worked with leadership to improve company culture and increase learning opportunities.

Software Engineer II

Eventbrite

Mar 2020 - Jun 2021 (1 year 4 months)

As part of Frontend Infrastructure, I built tools, pipelines, services, and scripts that allow EB's product teams to ship features with quality quickly, efficiently, and easily.

👂 Senior Software Engineer

Octerra

May 2019 - Feb 2020 (10 months)

Octerra spun out of StudioNow in late 2019. As a Senior Engineer, my responsibilities include developing new features for clients, establishing best practices, solving architectural level problems, and mentoring junior members.

Senior Software Engineer

StudioNow

Mar 2019 - May 2019 (3 months)

Software Engineer

StudioNow

Sep 2016 - Feb 2019 (2 years 6 months)

Maintaining & developing an Angular/AngularJS hybrid application powered by a Python based backend. Software is a Video Project Management & Bidding platform used by top brands & creative agencies.

Lead Developer

Video Ideas Productions

Jan 2015 - Sep 2016 (1 year 9 months)

Building and maintaining full stack web-based applications, as well as developing hybrid mobile applications for iOS and Android.

Video Producer

Video Ideas Productions

Sep 2014 - Sep 2016 (2 years 1 month)

SM Videographer/Photographer

Adventist Frontier Missions

2013 - 2014 (2 years)

Discover, Plan, Film, and Create the story of several missionaries serving in Africa - for airing on national television.

Education



Andrews University

Documentary Film

Skills

JavaScript • Python • Software Development • Video Production • Photography • Video Editing • Information Technology • Graphic Design • Web Design • Web Development